Previously on
Space Brothers
むった
＜不運に縁がある兄･六太と
ひびと
栄光の日 生まれの弟･日々人＞
Older brother Mutta is plagued by bad luck.
Born under a lucky star, younger brother Hibito becomes the first Japanese moonwalker.
＜日本人初のﾑｰﾝｳｫｰｶｰとなった
日々人のはるか後ろから➡
Older brother Mutta continues on his long quest to the moon,
月を目指し始めた兄･六太は
ついに 月のミッションの➡
having finally been selected as a backup member for a lunar mission.
バックアップクルーに
任命される＞
＜一方 月面での事故で
パニック障害となり➡
Meanwhile, a lunar accident has left Hibito struggling on the sidelines,
suffering from panic disorder.
前線から外された日々人は
復帰をかけた試験に臨む＞
But he's about to take a test to return to active duty.
＜なんとしてもこれを
クリアしなければ 日々人は➡
He must pass the test, or he will never go back to space.
二度と宇宙に
出ることができない＞
なんば
(南波日々人)うっ…あっ…｡
(ﾀﾞﾐｱﾝ)体温調節システムが
故障したらしい｡➡
My temperature regulation system is busted.
水の循環が
悪くなっているようで…➡
I'm not getting enough water...
体が凍りそうに寒い｡
My body is freezing.
さあ 行こう｡
Well, let's go.
(ﾊﾞﾃﾞｨ)ヒビトの酸素が
無くなっちまう！
Hibito's gonna run out of oxygen!
Stay calm, Buddy...
(ﾌﾚﾃﾞｨ)落ち着け バディ！
ハァ…帰ってきたぞ ダミアン｡
We made it out, Damian!
フレディ！バディ！こちら日々人｡
カレン！リンダ！応答してくれ！
Freddy! Buddy! This is Hibito!
Karen! Linda! Do you read me?
《酸素残量…８分｡➡
Eight minutes of oxygen left...
８分か クソッ！》
Eight minutes, huh?
Damn!
《時間だ…》
It's time...
うぅ！ぐああ…！
《くそ!!死ぬのか…！》
Damn!
Am I gonna die?
《体が…熱い！》
My body is burning up...
ああ…ああ…ハァハァ…｡
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)医師の見解では
ヘルメットの閉塞感が➡
The doctors believe that the helmet's confined space is triggering the panic attacks.
パニック発作を
誘発してるのだろうということだ｡
この変な症状…必ず治します｡
I'm going to find a way to get rid of this disorder.
I can't get lost in what I'm doing, nothing works out
I don't want these endlessly dull days
I hope I can move on
before the call of freedom drags me away
What's your wish?
I just want some real courage
We all stare doubt in the face, every one of us
Isn't the unpredictability of life the fun of it?
Devote your life to that dream you can't express
Let's go, advance against the wind, our road is long
Embrace the pain of it too
Take a big breath now, and yell
Big Bang! Chase it without fear!
I want to dream so badly it amazes me
There's cowardice in the way of your true wish
Rip that hot veil aside
現在
#91 How to Help Hibito
これにより
作業時間の大幅な短縮と➡
This will greatly reduce the time required for various tasks.
効率化をはかることが
可能になると考えられます｡
(南波六太)《まあ…大丈夫だろ
あいつなら》
Eh, he'll be fine...
(ｼｬﾛﾝ)⦅ねぇ ヒビト⦆
Say, Hibito...
⦅あなたがいつも六太の前に
いて 先に進み続けていれば➡
If you stay ahead of Mutta and lead the way,
ムッタはあなたに引っ張られて
前進できるわ⦆
Mutta will be right behind you.
(ｼｬﾛﾝ)⦅もしも あなたが
止まってしまったら➡
If you ever stop,
その時はきっと…⦆
I'm certain
(ｼｬﾛﾝ)⦅後ろから六太が あなたの
背中を押してくれる⦆
Mutta will give you a push from behind.
I've opened the DCM purge valve, but the warning hasn't stopped.
ディーシーエム
ＤＣＭパｰジバルブを開いたけど➡
ディスプレイの
警告表示が消えない｡
タスクの継続は不可能とみて
至急 エアロックに避難する｡
Since I won't be able to perform my assignment, I'm heading for the airlock.
(役員)ここで中断か｡
The test is being called off?
まあこれは
やむを得んでしょう｡
He's expected to stop.
大丈夫なんですか？
宇宙服内のＣＯ
濃度…｡
Is everything all right with the CO2 inside his spacesuit?
これも警報のみの
グリーンカードでしょう｡
It must be another green card that asked for a warning to come up.
私が出したものではないですが｡
But it isn't the green card I requested.
《心拍数が少し治まってきたか｡➡
His heart rate has slowed somewhat.
I was worried that he might suffer an attack...
あのまま発作を起こすかと
肝を冷やしたが》
《よく耐えたな ヒビト》
You really hung in there, Hibito...
《それにしてもゲイツ…➡
This is Gates's doing...
試験を中断に追い込むような
不要なカードを…》
He issued an unnecessary card, causing the test to be canceled...
(ゲイツ)管制官｡ゲイツだ｡
(管制官)はい｡
Mission Control, this is Gates.
Yes.
グリーンカードとして
“ＣＯ
センサー異常"の警告を➡
I'm issuing a green card to have a CO2 sensor malfunction warning displayed on the HUD of Hibito's helmet.
ヒビトのヘルメットスクリーンに
表示させろ｡
えっ いいんですか？
(無線:ゲイツの声)いいからやれ｡
Are you sure about that?
Just do it.
現在
(ｻｲﾓﾝ)室長！
Chief...
彼らが…｡
彼らが室長に話があると…｡
It seems they want to talk to you.
君たち…｡
You're...
エアロック内に入った｡➡
I'm in the airlock.
宇宙服に
アンビリカルコードを接続する｡
I'll hook up my spacesuit to the umbilical cord.
Okay, Hibito.
(無線:ジョンの声)ＯＫ ヒビト｡
《これが 意外と難しいんだよな》
This is harder than you'd think.
(ジョン)焦るなよ～ ヒビト｡
Be patient, Hibito.
I'm hooked up.
(無線:日々人の声)接続完了｡
(ﾛｰﾘｰ)よ～し！
Good!
ハッ！よし！警告表示が消えた｡
Okay, the warning's gone!
しばらく様子を見てから
再度 船外に出るよ｡
Once I confirm everything is fine, I'll head back out.
了解だ ヒビト｡
Roger that, Hibito.
フゥ…｡
《プリティドッグ…➡
Pretty Dog...
こんなもんが薬より効くとは…》
Never thought this would help more than drugs.
≪よう ヒビト｡聞こえるか？≫
Hey, Hibito... Can you hear me?
(無線:日々人の声)え？ああ…｡
Huh? Yeah...
《あれ…誰だ？》
Wait, who is that?
(無線)≪おいおい 俺が誰だか
気付いてねぇな≫
Dude... You don't know who this is?
頼むぜ ヒビト｡
一緒にカイコ食った仲だろ？
Come on, Hibito...
We ate silkworms together.
あ…バディ！
Buddy!
(ﾊﾞﾃﾞｨ)フッフッ！マメなムッタから
事細かに事情を聞いてな｡
I heard everything from Mutta.
今日のこの試験には
俺も来ると決めてたぜ｡
So I decided to come and watch your test today.
今 俺の隣に美女がいる｡
And right now, I have a pretty lady with me.
(カレン)ハロー ヒビト｡元気？
Hello, Hibito. Are you doing well?
カレン…｡
Karen...
フレディとリンダは
海外出張中だから➡
Freddy and Linda are currently working overseas, so they couldn't make it.
今日は来られなかったけど
２人には ちゃんとヒビトのこと➡
We told them what's going on.
伝えてあるから｡➡
｢ヒビトの試験が無事に
成功するように祈ってる｣って｡➡
They're praying that you'll pass the test.
２人とも遠くで
応援してくれてるわよ｡
You have support all around the world.
さて ヒビト｡
さっき 管制室から手順書を➡
Okay, Hibito.
I just swiped the manual from Mission Control.
かっぱらってきた｡
こっからは俺がキャプコムを➡
I'll be taking over as CAPCOM.
やらせてもらうぜ｡へっへっへ…｡
本当にいいんですか 室長？
気の合う仲間にやらせて｡
Are you sure about letting his friends handle this, Chief?
この試験は ヒビト君に
プレッシャーを与えて➡
Wasn't the purpose of this test to put Hibito under pressure, to see if a panic attack would result?
発作の有無を確認するためのもの
ではなかったのですか？
そうです｡
Yes, that was my intent.
最初は私も
そのつもりでしたけどね｡
彼らの言い分を聞いて
少し考えを変えました｡
But after hearing what they had to say, I changed my mind.
まずはハッチを開けて
船外に出よう｡
First, you need to open the hatch and go outside.
月面散歩だ｡
(無線:日々人の声)ＯＫ バディ！
Time for a lunar stroll.
Okay, Buddy!
転ぶなよ ヒビト｡ヘッヘッヘ…｡
Don't trip and fall, Hibito.
《なんか…懐かしい感じだ》
This feels very familiar.
そのまま太陽電池パネルの➡
Head straight for the solar panel Sunflower.
サンフラワーちゃんの方へ
向かってくれ｡
(無線:日々人の声)了解！
Got it.
おっと その前に 上方からの
ゴンドラに気をつけろ｡
Hold on. First, watch out for the gondola above you.
ゴンドラ？
Gondola?
何で？
Why?
何でってことはないだろ ヒビト｡
You have to ask why, Hibito?
船外活動は基本的に➡
EVAs are supposed to be done with a partner.
パートナーと２人でやるもんだ｡
ダミアン…｡
Damian...
ダミアンまで…来てくれたのか｡
You came, too?
当たり前だよ｡
You bet.
当たり前だ｡
How could I not...
さあ はじめよう ヒビト！
この月面なら➡
Well, let's get started, Hibito.
No need to worry about falling off a cliff on this moon.
落っこちる可能性もないしな｡
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)これは なんのための
試験なのか…｡➡
What is the purpose of this exercise?
ヒビトを試すためなのか…➡
Are we testing Hibito?
救うためなのか…｡
Or are we helping him?
私は後者のつもりでいましたが➡
I'd hoped to accomplish the latter,
やり方が
違ったのかもしれません｡
but it seems I had the wrong method.
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)ヒビトを独りにし
プレッシャーや恐怖心に➡
Isolating Hibito,
forcing him to overcome pressure and fear, was incorrect.
打ち勝たせようと
するのではなく…｡
Instead, we will help
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)ヒビトが一番…➡
Hibito remember his happiest moments.
しあわせ
幸福だった時のことを
思い出させてやる…｡
クルー
それが 同じ仲間である
彼らなりのヒビトの救い方です｡
That is how
Hibito's fellow crew members want to help him.
(職員)お疲れ様～｡明日の講習会も
同時刻から行いますので｡
Thanks for coming.
Tomorrow's class will begin at the same time.
ふ～終わった…｡
Whew, it's finally over...
《日々人の試験 あと
１５分ぐらいで終わりか…》
Hibito's test ends in another fifteen minutes?
エヌビーエル
《第２ＮＢＬ棟まで走れば
間に合いそ～だな…》
If I sprint over to NBL 2, I might make it in time.
《行くか…｡でもな～…➡
Should I go?
But you know...
“弟の応援のために走る兄"
なんて➡
It'd be embarrassing if someone saw a big brother sprinting over to support his little brother.
見られたら かなり
恥ずかしいもんがあるな…》
《よし！やめとこ！》
Okay, I won't go.
(北村)あ 南波君！
Nanba!
おっ？おお～北村さん!?
Kitamura?
久しぶり～！元気？
I haven't seen you in a while. How are you?
元気元気！
この食欲を見てよ ホラ！
I'm doing great! Just look at my appetite!
Oh, Serika should be here soon. She's over there.
あ せりかちゃんも
すぐ来るよ｡今あそこ｡
《ほえ～！》
Mind if I join you?
ご一緒して よろしいですか!?
ど～ぞど～ぞ｡
Go ahead.
いっただきま～す！
Let's eat!
ん～おいしい！でも ちょっと
盛りすぎたな こりゃ｡
Delicious!
But I might have gotten too much.
日本人の調理師が入ったらしいよ
ここの食堂｡
I heard the cafeteria hired a Japanese chef.
Huh? Really? I had no idea...
えっ そ～なんですか!?
知らなかった！
どうりで ごはんが
おいしいわけだ！よかったぁ｡
No wonder the food's so good... That's great.
ねえ 南波君｡
Hey, Nanba.
日々人君 今 試験中なんでしょ？
この後 見に行くの？
Isn't Hibito's taking his test now?
Are you going to check in on him?
いやあ～
もう終わってんじゃないかな｡
Nah, it's probably already over.
それに なんか…あれだよ｡
And you know...
兄弟なんて 普段はさ➡
At times like this,
遠くから見守るくらいが
ちょうどいいんだよ｡
it's better for brothers to keep their distance.
なるほど｡
I see...
でも ちょっと心配ですよね…｡
まだ大丈夫だよ たぶん｡
But you must be worried.
It probably isn't over yet...
私 さっき聞いたもん｡
試験は４０分延長だって｡
I just heard that the test was extended by forty-five minutes.
そっちに座ってた人たちが
言ってた｡
Huh?
That's what the people over there said.
絵名ちゃんの耳は
聖徳太子並みだからね｡
Ena has super sharp ears.
I hear all kinds of gossip...
噂話は入ってくんだよね～｡
《延長…》
Extended...
(北村)行ってきなよ 南波君｡
走れば まだ間に合うよ｡
You should go, Nanba.
If you run, you'll make it in time.
そうだね…｡
That's true.
《でもな～食った後 走ると
横っ腹が…》
But when I run after eating, my sides hurt.
なんつ～か…
“弟のために走る兄"というのは➡
Doesn't it seem a little weird for a big brother to run to watch his little brother?
ちょっと あれじゃない…？
カッコイイですよね｡
I think it's cool.
カッコイイですよ そ～いうの｡
Eh?
I think that kind of thing is really cool.
ですよね～！
Of course!
じゃあ ちょっくら
走って行ってくるかな！
Then I'll sprint over.
(北村)全部 食べてから行きなよ｡
あ…そうね…｡
First, finish your lunch.
Oh, right...
さて…じゃあ 今度こそ…➡
Okay, now I'm ready to go.
いってきま～す！
Bye!
うおぉ～～っ！
(無線:ﾊﾞﾃﾞｨの声)ヒビト ダミアン
次の作業に入るぞ｡
Hibito, Damian...
Time to move on to the next task.
ＯＫ！
Okay.
じゃあ“サンフラワー"の
電力送信ボックスに➡
Hook up the connector to the Sunflower's power transmitter.
コネクターを結合してくれ｡
(無線:日々人の声)了解！
Roger that.
We're getting a little hungry, Chief.
おなか減りましたね 室長｡
予定外のカードのために
遅れが出てしまいました｡
Due to an unexpected card, we're running over.
もうしばし ご辛抱を｡
Can you hang in there a little longer?
ダミアン｡手順書でパネルの
角度と向きの再確認を｡
Damian, can you check the manual for the panel's angle and direction?
(無線:ﾀﾞﾐｱﾝの声)ＯＫ！
Okay.
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)《ロナルド…｡➡
Ronald...
あの事故で受けた障害を
乗り越えられず➡
You weren't able to overcome your accident's aftereffects,
お前は 私の前から去った…｡➡
and you decided to leave...
ヒビトは 宇宙飛行士に戻るぞ》
Hibito's going to return to being an astronaut.
《あの時のお前に
見せてやりたいぜ ロナルド…》
I wish you could see this, Ronald.
(役員)それにしても➡
Still, Hibito's heart rate is rather high.
ヒビト君は心拍数が
高いままだね｡大丈夫なのかねぇ｡
Is he all right?
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)確かに 正常値では
ないような…
It does appear to be higher than normal.
たぶんこれは 問題ありません｡
I don't believe there's any problem.
ヒビトは月にいた時も
ずっと こんなもんでしたよ｡
When Hibito was on the moon,
his heart rate was always this fast.
軽い興奮状態です｡
It's because he's excited.
焦りや緊張ではありません｡
Not because he's worried or nervous.
あと少しで終わりだぞ ヒビト！
We're almost done, Hibito.
Yeah.
なあ ヒビト…｡
Hey, Hibito...
俺もバディもカレンも…
みんないるんだ｡
You have me, Buddy, Karen, and everyone else.
これからも
それを忘れないでくれよ｡
Don't forget that!
ヒビトの復帰を願ってるのは
ヒビトだけじゃないんだ｡
You aren't the only one who wants to see you back in space.
フフ…ありがと｡
Thanks.
《そうだ…本当にそうだ…》
Yeah... He's right.
《どれだけの人が…
俺のことを思ってくれた…》
There are many people who showed concern for me.
俺は 宇宙飛行士…｡
I am an astronaut.
おい ヒビト｡そっちから行くな｡
足元に機材が落ちてんぞ！
Hey, Hibito...
Don't go that way.
There's machinery in the way.
《俺は…》
I am...
《宇宙飛行士！》
an astronaut!
寒み～ 外！
It's freezing outside!
あ～横っ腹…｡
My sides...
《｢おう 日々人 お疲れさん！｣》
Hey, Hibito... Good work.
《｢発作とか出なかったか？｣》
あ～しんど…｡
Any attacks?
Th-This is killing me...
《｢例のお守り 役に立ったろ｣》
I bet that good luck charm helped.
《｢まあ お前なら やれると
思ってたぜ｣てな感じで…》
Well, I knew you could do it.
That should work.
Thanks.
おめでとう ヒビト！
Congratulations, Hibito!
よくやった！
おめでとう ヒビト｡
Great job!
Congrats, Hibito.
ハァ…ハァ…｡
チクショー 日々人…！
Damn it, Hibito...
俺の横っ腹 返せ…｡
I killed my sides for nothing.
The starlight illuminates my future, it's wow... truth
It's 3 AM, and I dream awake
With no idea of my future
only impatience consumes me
I have a thorn in my heart that won't allow me to lose to him
I'm walking a path of thorns I made for myself
But I won't forget the love I found
And I won't forget the ones close to me
I realized you cannot live your life alone
The starlight illuminates my future, and we are all shooting stars
My holy wishes turn all our sad lies into something better
Our orbits have gotten separated,
but I'm fine if you are close
Next time, on
Space Brothers
#92 Lonely People
Hibito has completed his test,
＜日々人が復帰試験を終えた中
私は ついに➡
and I finally train with astronauts who will be going to the moon!
月へ 一緒に行くメンバーとの
訓練に臨む＞
(ﾊﾞﾄﾗｰ)＜あれは 一癖も二癖もある
連中の寄せ集めです＞
This crew has some very unique characters.
Next time, on Space Brothers:
"Lonely People"